Summary

I am a User Experience Designer with over eighteen years in digital design. As a User Experience Designer, my in-depth understanding of the design process allows me to meet user goals while balancing aesthetics and technical constraints. I design comprehensive design systems leveraging my extensive background in web design and development.

Professional Experience

KBS March 2015-present

Associate Director, User Experience

November 2016-present

- Designed a 3D cabinet configurator for Stanley Black & Decker. Created a design system, user flows, usability tests, and comprehensive prototypes
- Built a skills matrix for the UX team to help visualize strengths and gaps.
 Established a Sketch and InVision workflow to streamline work between the UX, Design, and Development departments
- Led a design discovery to redesign the PODS website. Delivered a UX audit, competitive research, personas, journey maps, and usability testing

Senior User Experience Designer

March 2015-November 2015

- I led the responsive redesign of BMWUSA.com. Built a modular design system, responsive grid, wireframes, user flows, and prototypes
- Redesigned the sign up flows for the My BMW website. Created wireframes, user flows, interaction and technical documentation, and prototypes
- Designed a learning site for digital marketers at Hershey. Conducted user and stakeholder interviews, designed content types, and wireframes

New York University

October 2008-March 2015

User Experience Specialist

Digital Communications Group, Information Technology Services August 2014–March 2015

- Designed and developed a new responsive user interface for Sakai—an open source Learning Management System. Wrote new HTML 5 templates and a Sass based CSS framework. Incorporated the user experience and user interface improvements from. NYU Classes
- Redesigned and prototyped a new user interface for NYU's Email Direct—a bulk email communication tool for NYU administrators

User Experience Designer

Academic Technology Services, Information Technology Services October 2011–August 2014

- Redesigned and developed a new user interface for NYU Classes—their Learning Management System (LMS). The redesign was based on extensive usability testing and research
- Created a 'Mobile First' prototype for our redesign of <u>MediaCommons</u>—a digital network for professors and post-graduate students of film and media studies

UX/UI Skills

- Design Systems, Style Guides, & Visual Design
- Sketching, Storyboarding, & Paper Prototyping
- Wireframing, Card Sorting, & High-fidelity Prototyping
- · Usability Testing, User Interviews, & Personas

Technical Skills

- Sketch, Photoshop, Illustrator, InVision, Principle
- Markup (HTML) & Styling (CSS)
- · Sass, Javascript & jQuery, Grunt & Gulp
- · Git & SVN, PHP, MySQL, Drupal

Interactive Designer and Developer

Faculty Technology Services, Information Technology Services
October 2008–October 2011

- Designed and developed <u>MediaCommons—a digital</u> network for professors and post-graduate students—using Drupal
- Established a distinctive look and feel for the MediaCommons network and it's project sites
- Designed and developed two platforms for viewing the digital collections of NYU Libraries. Allowing patrons to view both image based collections scanned books and photographs—and stream audio and video collections

Columbia University

August 2001-September 2008

Senior Web Designer and Developer

Columbia University Digital Knowledge Ventures (a small 'digital agency' within Columbia University)

May 2005-September 2008

 Designed and developed educational course content and departmental websites for Columbia University and affiliated non-profits

Web Designer and Developer

Columbia University Digital Knowledge Ventures August 2001–May 2005

- Worked with Columbia University faculty to design and develop interactive eseminars and courses
- Designed and developed interactive maps, audio slideshows, podcasts, and video production and post-production for streaming video and DVD

Scholastic

January 2000-May 2001

Web Designer

e-Scholastic

- Designed educational, commercial, and promotional websites for Scholastic
- Designed daily site graphics, interactive quizzes, and educational activities

Teaching

The New School, Fall 2004-Spring 2008

Adjunct faculty member, Media Studies

 Courses: Foundations of Media Design, Digital Video Effects, and Motion Graphics with After Effects

Columbia University, Summer 2005–Summer 2008

Instructor, High School Program

• Course: Digital Filmmaking: From Initial Concept to Final Edit

Education

1999–2007 **Ph.D. Media & Communication**, European Graduate School, Saas-Fee, Switzerland

1998-2001 Certificate in Film Production, The New School, New York, NY

1995–1996 M.Phil. Medieval History, Trinity College, Dublin University, Ireland

1991-1994 B.A. History and Philosophy, University College Dublin, Ireland

Additional Information

Organizations

- Co-Founder: NYU UX Group & NYU Web Designers and Developers Group
- Co-Organizer: DrupalCamp NYC 9 & 10 NYC Drupal Users Group
- Member: IxDA NYC UXPA Gotham Sass Meetup NYC Drupal Users Group Agile Experience Design Meetup Type Directors Club

Selected Presentations, Event Organization, and Trainings

Presentations

- Better Tools for a Better Process at KBS' Bits & Bites 23rd March, 2017
- Beyond Putting Lipstick on the Pig at EdUI 2014 30th September, 2014
- Sakai: Meet MORPHEUS at Open Apereo 2014 2nd June, 2014
- Rapid Prototyping Techniques at TorchTech: UX Networking Breakfast 23rd April, 2014
- Fixing Broken User Experience at NYU ITS All Hands Meeting 21st September, 2012
- MediaCommons 2.0 at Digital Library Federation Forum 5th May, 2009

Event Organization

- UX Networking Breakfast Co-Organizer TorchTech & NYU UX group 23rd April, 2014
- UX @ NYU Co-Organizer NYU UX group 14th November, 2013
- Usability @ NYU Co-Organizer NYU UX group 11th December, 2012
- DrupalCamp NYC 9 & 10 Co-Organizer & Designer NYC Drupal Users Group June & December 2011

Trainings

- Design Teams Are a Design Exercise: How to Build, Inspire and Keep Design Teams (Happy) with Alberta Soranzo & Martina Hodges-Schell, Interaction 17 — February 2017
- Leading Creative Ideation with Christian Linsey & Jen Zhao, Cooper U May 2016
- Design Leadership with Teresa Brazen & Lane Halley, Cooper U August 2015
- Scaling User Interfaces with Amy Schade, Nielsen Norman Group August 2014
- UX Leadership with Kim Goodwin, Rosenfeld Media October 2012
- Do It Yourself Usability Testing with Steve Krug, Rosenfeld Media May 2012
- Sketching Interfaces with Jason Mesut & Sam Smith, Interaction 12 February 2012
- Mobile Prototyping Essentials with Rachel Hinman, Interaction 12 February 2012